<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>Practical Machine Learning Course</title><link>https://compositelearning.com/</link><description>Practical Machine Learning Course by Denis Akhiyarov and Ruslan Ishkildin</description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" rel="self" href="https://compositelearning.com/rss.xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2018 &lt;a href="mailto:denis.akhiyarov@gmail.com"&gt;CompositeLearning&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 05:08:01 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://compositelearning.com/posts/introduction/</link><dc:creator>CompositeLearning</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;h2&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a course developed by engineers for newcomers to machine learning, who would like to build practical machine learning models without going too much into theoretical foundations of the machine learning algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course assumes basic knowledge of programming, high-school math, probability and statistics theory, minimization methods, and linear algebra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The materials cover 2 major types of machine learning: unsupervised learning, and supervised learning. Reinforcement learning is not covered in this course due to complexity of this subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unsupervised learning is mainly concerned with clustering analysis, dimensionality reduction, and anomaly detection. These methods are typically used for analyzing the dataset, when training labels for supervised learning are not available or when quick insights into hidden relationship between features are sought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The supervised machine learning can be divided into shallow learning and deep learning based on the complexity of methods, but also into classification and regression based on the continuous values and class labels for output predictions respectively. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course is using open-source libraries in Jupyter Notebooks hosted in Azure Notebooks or Google Colab:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Python, Pandas, numpy, matplotlib, Scikit-Learn, TensorFlow, Keras, Jupyter&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://compositelearning.com/posts/introduction/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 05:01:31 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>